in today's video we're going to do
something a little bit fancy and an
ultra low sugar strawberry SBO with a
balsamic
[Music]
glaze yeah we're going to do something a
little bit different here I don't
normally go Fancy with flavors but you
know strawberries and balsamic vinegar
it's a very common popular flavor
combination in fancy restaurants and you
know the world of the internet
whatever that was um there's a couple of
things I'm not making this zero sugar
because there's no point strawberries
have a fair bit of sugar in them anyway
so making this zero sugar with other
things you're actually just dropping the
sugar amount so we're going to make this
low sugar going to use xylol to do that
I'm going to add corn syrup for a
texture change because corn syrup does
something very unique to sawway and ice
cream if you don't want to use that then
don't it will have effect on the recipe
it won't be as good as it could be but
it will still be good we're going to do
it in the Ninja creamy because sways
work really really well in the creamy
we've got a nice few ingredients here
for those people that are going to ask
me can you use arrol the answer is no I
will do a video on arrol in the next
week or two to explain why you shouldn't
use that in your ice cream and/ or sbet
but for now we're going to use tarum
it's an excellent stabilizer it does
need heating so let's get going and get
this super delicious strawberry sbet
going so the first thing we're going to
need to do is weigh out our strawberries
I'm going to make this one tub size one
ninja creamy tub size so we need 135 G
of strawberries we're going to process
these on the hob and bring the mixture
down we're going to evaporate some of
that water so we're just going to give
it a helping hand and chop up our
strawberry into
quarters like so with our strawberries
in there we can now combine the rest of
the ingredients so let's shift this out
the way we need to add to that
264 G of water this is going to come
straight from the
tap 264 G of water move this out the way
and into this we're going to add 68 G of
xylol there aren't many sugar
substitutes that are actually good in
ice cream xylol is
okay 68
G have to be pretty careful cuz it has a
really strong effect on the freezing
point if you like you know 68
G if you put in 75 G you're starting to
get to the point where it won't freeze
so we need to be careful here which is
why a gram scale is really important in
scientific based ice cream and sbet
making so with that in here we are going
to
add half a gram of sea salt it's like a
good pinch more than anything else and
because we're not aiming for zero sugar
again no point strawberries got sugar in
them we're going to add in corn syrup or
invert sugar 30 G and
that is for Tex texure there we go
that's for texture that changes the
texture of any ice cream or sbet more
than you could ever imagine so the last
thing we need to do is
our is our stabilizer going to use tarum
and 0.5
G of our tarum now what do we need to do
is we need to get this onto a steady
heat and get these strawberries cooked
and softened
so we can get our pan on top
here and just stir it a little bit we
we're going to disolve that xylol into
our water we're creating the equivalent
of a sugar syrup here and we're going to
cook our strawberries down in those
until they're soft enough to break apart
with a whisk or a fork this will take
about 10 or 15 minutes max with our
strawberries softened they're just
pushing up against the side of the pan
and completely falling apart which means
that they're ready we can turn the heat
off and take it off that hot plate we
want this to cool down for about 10
minutes right this is still hot and
we're going to just put it in this
container we want that to cool down it's
not safe to put hot liquids in a blender
so we're going to give that 5 10
minutes right with with this cooled down
enough make sure that Lids on
properly we're going to pulse this to
start
with and now we're just going to put it
on low for about 20 to 30
seconds cuz the liquid is warm in here
still be careful taking a lid off if you
do this with hot mixture it will burst
out the
top like that and that's the pressure
building inside due to the hot air so be
careful but when we take the lid off
we've got this
amazing strawberry smell this can go
straight into
um there we go we got a little tiny bit
left over this may settle down but it's
about it's about 15 or 20 m it's not a
lot all over me oh that tast good so now
this can go straight into your freezer
to harden off now quick tidy up we're
going to move on to the balsamic
glaze and for the balsamic
glaze we're going
to put some in we're going to reduce it
down on the hob there you go so that's
yeah it's about 100 Mil
something like that and we're just going
to reduce it down on the hob there's no
point me filming this just going to put
on hob simmer it gently and reduce it
down by half you can see that it's
leaving that glaze on the bottom of the
pan all right that's the indication that
we're pretty much where we need to
be and it'll be ready for when our sbit
is completely Frozen so let's get this
out of the pan into a little container
and we'll come back in a couple of
hours so with your ninja creamy tub in
the freezer you will see that it will
start to layer up and that's just the
solids combining and the water
separating just Stir It All Back
Together put it straight back in the
freezer taken out of the freezer so
you've stirred it in the freezer during
the freezing process mix that solid
layer back in it's going to happen with
a high fruit solids SB
let's get it
[Music]
spinning we're looking good
right time
to get the machine off the top and get
some dished up
[Music]
there we have our strawberry sbet ultra
low sugar with our balsamic glaze what
you can do if you're just going to eat
it out the tub in the creamy is take a
chopstick and just make some
holes down through it all the way to the
bottom and then pour some of your glaze
in there you don't want too much cuz
it's strong we've reduced it it's super
strong flavor but we've dished some up
in a bowl so you can see it let's get
this back in the
freezer the balsamic
glaze super strong the strawberry SB
smells delicious excellent
[Music]
texture that's the
money
yeah
delicious obviously the idity of the
balsamic glaze cut straight through the
sweetness of the strawberry saw by using
xylol which has a strong effect on the
freezing point of any frozen dessert ice
cream sbet sheret etc mean you cannot
use the same amount as you would do with
normal sugar you have to account for
that if a standard recipe calls for 150
g of standard sugar you put 150 g of
zyol in it's not going to freeze at all
it will stay liquid the entire time so
you need to learn about the freezing
point depression of the sugar substitute
that you're using what we have here is
an incredible texture super delicious
ultra low sugar strawberry sbet if you
don't want to use the corn syrup or
invert sugar then don't but that does
make the texture so much better
obviously strawberries have about 5%
sugar naturally so we can't do zero
sugar recipe here there 5% of that
weight of strawberries is sugar but by
using silol we can keep that processed
sugar
down with only the inclusion of that
corn syrup or invert sugar give this one
a try you will not be disappointed it's
super easy to do too so thanks for much
for watching don't forget to like And
subscribe and I'll see you next time
[Music]